#### SPC Matthew A Levandowski

10897 48th Ave Suite BB5 Allendale, MI 49401-8142

Mobile Phone: 315.286.2383 Email: levandma@mail.gvsu.edu URL: http://www2.gvsu.edu/~levandma/

## **Professional Objective**

Experienced military leader with documented success in responsible and challenging positions; seeking a position to gain work related experience in order to progress to higher level positions. Proven record of accomplishment, mission-critical decision making, time-management, and extensive teamwork abilities; with the ability to develop and implement effective action plans. I have fulfilled a tour of duty in Afghanistan and four years of military service with an honorable discharge.

# **Employment History**

### Reserve Specialist / Truck Driver

180th TC, US Army Reserve (Muskegon, Michigan)

August 2009-Present

Train on various soldier skills and wheeled truck driving. Plan and execute regular training excersises in support of the 180th Transportation Company.

#### **Advertisement Setter**

Kohls Department Store (Muskegon, Michigan)

November 2009-Present

Work with other associates as a team to inventory and assess advertisement pricing and policies for entire store. Assist customers and perform customer service tasks.

#### **Telecommunications Line Installer**

Shareco Communications (Grand Rapids, Michigan)

March 2008-November 2008

As a line installer I was responsible for the installation, repair, and termination of various broadband cabling, including fiber optic splicing and installation, CAT5E, CAT6, 100-pair copper wire and various others. Also installed video cabling and security cameras.

### **Communications Specialist OEF VII**

US Army (Afghanistan)

February 2006-July 2007

Deployed to Afghanistan in support of Operation Enduring Freedom as a communication specialist for a support battion with a company sized element with more than 150 employees.

#### Achievements:

- Participated in the Joint Task Force as security for the occupying NATO and ISAF forces.
- Participated in the successful repatriation of a US Soldier in a Search and Rescue Mission.

### 25F Network Switching Systems Operator / Maintainer

10th Mountain Division, US Army (Fort Drum, New York)

August 2005-February 2006

Communications specialist directly responsible for the installation, maintenance, and repair of over half a million dollars of communication equipment for a company with over 150 soldiers.

### Achievements:

- Participated in sucessfull training at JROTC in Fort Polk, Loiusiana.
- Conducted numerous training excersises successfully in light infantry.

### **Education**

BA in Computer Science (minor in Information Systems), November 2009–Present

Grand Valley State University (Allendale, MI)

Subjects: Java Programming (A), Speech (A-).

ASA in Associates in Science and Arts, August 2009. Graduated after returning from the Army.

Muskegon Community College (Muskegon, MI)

Subjects: Physics (A-).

HS Diploma, June 2001. Graduated Top 15 in class.

Oakridge High School (Muskegon, MI)

Overall GPA: 3.5

### **Technical Skills**

Programming Skills: Java (intermediate), C++ (beginner), XHTML/CSS (intermediate), Perl (beginner).

*Telecommunication Skills:* Fiber Optic Installation / Splicing (1 year experience), Cat5e and Cat6 Installation (intermediate), Network Routing Infrastructure (beginner).

*Military Skillset:* General Dynamics C4 - MSE (3 years experience), COMTECH MTS and BlueForce Tracker, SIPR and NIPR, SINCGARS Radios, SMART-T Satellite.

#### References

SGT

Robert

Bowyer

US

Army

Reserve

Phone:

231.571.8576

Email:

bowyer.robert@us.army.mil

SFC

Jamie

Staten

US

Army

Phone:

315.286.8069

Email:

staten.jamie@us.army.mil

Shawn

Zimmerman

Shareco

Phone:

616.292.0549

Email:

shawnshawnz@aol.com

Keith

Hannah

**Kohls** 

Phone:

231.740.3242

Email:

keith1139@hotmail.com

## **Academic Memberships:**

National Honors Society

Student Veteran Organiation

CS Study Group

Total Trek Quest

## **Security Clearance**

• Secret, US Army, 2012

## **Military Awards and Honors**

• **Joint Service Achievement Medal**, Secretary of Defense, May 2007

Received for **meritorious** service, as a Guard Force Member for a Joint Task Force in support of Operation Enduring Freedom.

• ISAF Medal Afghanistan, NATO, 2007

For support of the **ISAF** operations in Afghanistan.

• Army Commendation Medal, US Army, 2007

For **outstanding** performance in the 3rd Infantry Brigade Combat Team, 10th Mountain Division.

- Army Certification of Achievement, US Army, 2006
- Army Good Conduct Medal (2), US Army, 2007

Last modified 22 January 2010.

Copyright © 2010 by Matthew Levandowski.

All rights reserved. This document may not be changed or distributed without permission.